<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Thibault Vatter</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Thibault Vatter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Thibault Vatter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About me In 2016, I obtained a PhD in Statistics from HEC Lausanne under the supervision of Valérie Chavez-Demoulin. As a recipient of a fellowship from the Swiss National Science Foundation, I then conducted my postdoctoral research in the group of Richard Davis at Columbia University. I am now an assistant professor in the statistics department at Columbia University.
I am currently working on diverse methodological and applied projects, ranging from solving statistical learning problems using copulas to modeling time-series of counts semiparametrically, and from building high-dimensional risk models for thousands of assets to developing new causal discovery algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>In preparation Ackerer, D., and Tagasovska, N., and Vatter, T. (2019)
Autoencoded scenario generation
Ackerer, D., and Tagasovska, N., and Vatter, T. (2019)
Deep Smoothing of the Implied Volatility Surface
Vatter, T., Ackerer, D. and Nagler, T. (2019)
High-Dimensional Pair-Copula Constructions with Financial Applications
Davis, R. A., Vatter, T., and Zhang, J. (2019)
Modeling Time Series of Counts with Shape Constraints
De Treville, S., Hoffstetter, J. and Vatter, T. (2019)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/home/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/software/</guid>
      <description>C++ vinecopulib High-performance C++ library for vine copula modeling based on Boost and Eigen
R rvinecopulib R interface to the vinecopulib C++ library
kde1d Efficient implementation of univariate local polynomial kernel density estimators that can handle bounded and discrete data.
gamCopula Generalized additive models for bivariate conditional dependence structures and vine copulas
VineCopula Statistical inference of vine copulas
copulaDAG Copula-based causal discovery and directed acyclic graphs, accompanies the paper Nonparametric Quantile-based Causal Discovery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>2019:
 Computational Statistics and Introduction to Data science (STAT GU5206) Statistical Inference (STAT GU4204)   2018:
 Statistical Inference (STAT GU4204, STAT GR5204 ) Time series analysis (STAT GU4221, GR5221)   2017:
 Math Methods for Political Science (POLS GU4700)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>/home/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>